Degradation of the world’s natural resources by humans is rapidly outpacing the planet’s ability to absorb the damage, a recent UN environmental study has found.
联合国最近的一项环境研究发现，人类导致的世界自然资源退化，正迅速超出地球消化这种损害的能力。
The study concludes that without radical action the level of prosperity that millions of people in the developed world count on will be impossible to maintain or extend to poorer countries.
该研究得出结论：如果不采取彻底的行动，发达国家数以百万计的人所依赖的繁荣水平将既无法维持，也无法推广到较贫穷的国家。
Water scarcity is the curse of some of the poorest regions on Earth, leaving developing countries increasingly unable to feed themselves, and causing hardship for millions of people.
水资源短缺是地球上一些最贫穷地区的祸根，使发展中国家越来越无力养活自己，也给数以百万计的人带来苦难。
There appears little prospect of this desperate situation being remedied without radical action being taken.
看来，如果不采取彻底的行动，这一危急局面几乎没有补救的希望。
Water sources are under increasing threat from population growth, climate change, rapid urbanisation, rising levels of consumption, and the degradation of lands that previously provided a natural replenishment of water resources.
水源正日益受到人口增长、气候变化、快速城市化、消费水平不断提高以及土地退化的威胁，而这些土地过去曾为水资源提供自然补充。
The rate of damage to the natural environment was found to increase globally, despite concerted efforts to persuade governments to take measures to improve the condition.
研究发现，尽管各方齐心协力，劝说各国政府采取措施改善环境状况，但在全球范围内，自然环境遭受损害的速度仍在加快。
“If current trends continue, and the world fails to improve patterns of production and consumption, then the state of the world’s environment will continue to decline,” warned UN executive director Achim Steiner.
联合国执行主任阿希姆·施泰纳警告说：“如果目前的趋势持续下去，而世界又未能改善生产和消费模式，那么世界环境状况将继续恶化。”
He said the tools for improving the environment for millions of people existed in developed countries, but were in danger of not being used.
他说，发达国家拥有为数以百万计的人改善环境的手段，但这些手段有被闲置的危险。
The study found that basic measures to tackle some of the key causes of environmental damage were still not being taken.
研究发现，针对造成环境损害的一些关键原因，人们仍未采取基本的应对措施。
These included measures to reduce air pollution; to control the damage to marine ecosystems, which can have a huge effect on fish stocks on which hundreds of millions of people depend; and to curb the degradation of land where modern agricultural methods were pursued without regard to the longer-term consequences.
这些措施包括：减少空气污染；控制对海洋生态系统的损害，这种损害可能对数亿人所依赖的鱼类资源产生巨大影响；以及在推行现代农业方法而不顾较长远后果的地方遏制土地退化。
Despite the recent global agreement on cutting greenhouse gas emissions, global carbon output continues to rise.
尽管最近全球就削减温室气体排放达成了协议，全球碳排放量仍在继续上升。
This will put a long-term strain on the ability of developing economies to feed their own people.
这将使发展中经济体养活本国人民的能力长期承受压力。
Climate change is aggravated by the emissions of greenhouse gases from chemical and natural fertilisers used in agriculture, which increased by more than a quarter between 2000 and 2010.
农业中使用的化学肥料和天然肥料排放温室气体，使气候变化加剧；2000年至2010年间，这类排放量增加了四分之一以上。
Other problem areas identified in the report included glaciers, which provide vital water resources for millions of people, but which are shrinking as the climate warms.
报告指出的其他问题领域包括冰川：冰川向数以百万计的人提供至关重要的水资源，但正随着气候变暖而萎缩。
In rich countries, these problems have built up over decades and centuries while economic growth was pursued at the expense of the environment.
在富裕国家，这些问题是几十年乃至几百年间逐渐积累起来的，其间人们以牺牲环境为代价追求经济增长。
Subsequent efforts to remedy the damage have met with partial success.
后来为补救这些损害所做的努力取得了部分成功。
But in developing countries, the path of future development has more potential to change, which has encouraged international institutions to devise more sustainable growth pathways that are supposed both to alleviate poverty and to preserve the environment.
但在发展中国家，未来的发展道路有更大的改变潜力，这促使国际机构设计更可持续的增长路径，这些路径理应既能减轻贫困，又能保护环境。